<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wil thomason</title>
    <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on wil thomason</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:22:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wbthomason.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/publications</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:22:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbthomason.github.io/publications</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbthomason.github.io/papers/iser2016_unfamiliargestures.pdf&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zero-Shot Learning for Unfamiliar Gesture Recognition&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Wil Thomason and Ross Knepper.
Accepted to and presented at ISER 2016&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&amp;ldquo;An Accurate Real-Time RFID-Based Location System&amp;rdquo;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Kirti Chawla, Christopher McFarland, Gabriel Robins, and Wil Thomason.
Accepted to IJRFITA.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;presentations&#34;&gt;Presentations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&amp;ldquo;Recognizing Unfamiliar Gestures for Human-Robot Interaction through Zero-Shot Learning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Wil Thomason.
Given at RSS 2016 in the 2nd Workshop on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ece.rochester.edu/projects/rail/mlhrc2016/&#34;&gt;Model Learning for Human-Robot
Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grants&#34;&gt;Grants&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-author of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1646417&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Synergy: Coordinated Action Among Independent Mobile Cyber-Physical
Systems&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; with Ross
Knepper, Greg Morrisett, and Abhishek Anand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/projects</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:22:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbthomason.github.io/projects</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cornell-rpal/unfamiliar-gestures&#34;&gt;unfamiliar gestures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;My current research project seeks to create and analyze a framework capable of
inferring meaning from unfamiliar human gestures. In interactions between
humans, we frequently assume shared contextual knowledge and common grounding.
This allows us to make gestures without a guarantee that our conversational
partners are familiar with them, but maintain a reasonable level of certainty
that we will be understood. Although this is a desirable ability for human-robot
interactions, current approaches to understanding gestures, natural language, or
the fusion thereof, fall short in this area. By applying techniques from
zero-shot learning to a novel frequency-domain gestural feature description, we
have achieved some success at solving this problem. This project is ongoing.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cornell-rpal/rosbeam&#34;&gt;rosbeam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;As part of an effort to enable the Beam Remote Presence Device to be usable as
a platform for robotic development, I updated and improved upon a project to
reverse engineer the Beam&amp;rsquo;s motor control interface and provide a ROS wrapper.
Starting from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xlz/rosbeam&#34;&gt;prior work&lt;/a&gt;, this entailed a rewriting of the
primary mechanism used to enable execution of foreign code. The internals of the
Beam software had changed significantly since the original project was created,
so the rewriting was a good opportunity to also restructure the code. Doing so
resulted in a much more future-proof implementation of the original approach.
The project was fairly short and easy, and is currently being used in the
experimental verification phase of another research effort into algorithms for
social navigation.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal&#34;&gt;Personal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason/bork&#34;&gt;bork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;bork has gone through a number of iterations of purpose, but is currently
targeted at being a robust, fast, and easy to use AUR helper. More to come as I
continue to work on the project.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason/minigrade&#34;&gt;minigrade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Minigrade is fundamentally a powerful, extensible autograding server. Created
originally for a class I TAed in undergrad, it sought to provide a lightweight,
secure, and fast server for grading programming assignments by running test
cases and streaming the results back to the user. In the implementation of the
test case/evaluation side of things, an interesting mechanism for describing
partial evaluation states was created and added. I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of rewriting
Minigrade in &lt;a href=&#34;http://elixir-lang.org&#34;&gt;Elixir&lt;/a&gt; for increased performance and
robustness.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason/drunk-uncle&#34;&gt;drunk uncle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Drunk Uncle (named for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nbc.com/saturday-night-live/cast/bobby-moynihan-15336/character/drunk-uncle-16241&#34;&gt;Bobby Moynihan character&lt;/a&gt;) is an automated
argument system. It started as a project at HackDuke, and was rewritten
afterward for performance and capability. Essentially, given an opinionated
statement on a subject, Drunk Uncle determines the sentiment and subject of the
statement and searches the Internet for evidence against the statement. This
evidence is then presented to the user in an insulting manner. The system is
only a novelty, and I do not recommend its use by anyone for anything, ever.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason/ironkernel&#34;&gt;ironkernel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;IronKernel was one of the first kernels written in Rust, back when the
language was in version 0.8 or so. Though it&amp;rsquo;s now little more than a curiosity,
given how fast the language has evolved and the creation of more robust kernels
and operating systems (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redox-os/redox&#34;&gt;redox&lt;/a&gt;), it
was a fun project at the time, and achieved a degree of notice in the Rust
community.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason/botulism&#34;&gt;botulism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In undergrad, I worked as a TA for a class offered both to the open Internet
and students at my university. We needed an IRC bot for the course to
communicate with students outside of the university, so, as a simple exercise, I
wrote botulism - a Python library for IRC bots and a sample bot implemented
using the library. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain that there are more fully-featured, robust
libraries for this purpose by now, but botulism remains one of the simplest I&amp;rsquo;ve
seen, and served its purpose well.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links</title>
      <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/fixed/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:22:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbthomason.github.io/fixed/links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site contains references to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://wbthomason.github.io/assets/W.Thomason_CV.pdf&#34;&gt;CV&lt;/a&gt;, a list of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://wbthomason.github.io/publications&#34;&gt;publications and
presentations&lt;/a&gt;, descriptions of a selection of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://wbthomason.github.io/projects&#34;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt;, my
(infrequently updated) &lt;a href=&#34;https://wbthomason.github.io/blog&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason&#34;&gt;Github profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/contact</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:22:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbthomason.github.io/contact</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can be contacted through any of the below media, given in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wbthomason ( at ) {my department, abbr.}.{my university}.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;{firstname}.{lastname}@{Google&amp;rsquo;s mail service}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wilthomason&#34;&gt;@wilthomason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wbthomason&#34;&gt;wbthomason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skype: Request via email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/about</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:22:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbthomason.github.io/about</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;about-photo&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://wbthomason.github.io/media/about-photo.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Wil Thomason, a second-year PhD student in computer science at Cornell.  My
primary research interests are in robotics, though I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in
programming languages, algorithms, machine learning, and interdisciplinary
efforts among these areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in algorithms for efficient cooperation in
heterogeneous multi-agent scenarios. I want teams of humans and arbitrary
robotic systems to be able to work together in a manner which both &amp;ldquo;feels&amp;rdquo;
natural (i.e.  equivalent to or better than working with a team of humans
alone) and is efficient and effective (i.e. utilizes differences in
capabilities between the agents well, eliminates redundant work, allows for the
accomplishment of tasks flexibly and quickly, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.cornell.edu/~rak/&#34;&gt;Professor Ross Knepper&lt;/a&gt; on projects related to
situated gestural understanding, contextual language understanding, and multi-agent planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://wbthomason.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbthomason.github.io/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;home&#34;&gt;

  &lt;ul class=&#34;post-list&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;{% render about.md %}&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;{% render links.md %}&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;{% render contact.md %}&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>